现在，我们将看一个更加数学化的方式来描述投影过程，投影
Now, we're going to look at a more mathematical way to describe the projection process, projection
从现实世界到图像平面的一点。在上一讲中，我们研究了它
of a point from the real world into the image plane. In the last lecture, we looked at it
从非常直观和几何的角度来看。这一次，我们将更多地关注它
from a very intuitive and geometric perspective. This time, we're going to look at it more
数学。我们将使用不同的投影
mathematically. We're going to use a different projection
我们上次使用的模型。我们将使用一种被称为“中心”的模型
model to what we used last time. We're going to use a model that's referred to as the "central
投影“模型。这个模型的关键元素是我们的相机坐标框架
projection" model. The key elements of this model are the cameras coordinate frame we
由C表示。图像平面与摄像机的x和y轴平行并位于
denote by C. The image plane is parallel to the camera's x and y axis and positioned at
正z方向上的距离F.F相当于焦距
a distance F in the positive z direction. F is equivalent to the focal length of the
我们在上一次讲座中谈过的镜头。现在为了突出重点，我们是什么
lens that we talked about in the last lecture. Now in order to project the point, what we
我们是通过图像平面从原点投射光线到原点
do is we cast a ray from the point in the world through the image plane to the origin
相机使用中央投影模型，您会注意到图像是非反转的
of the camera. With the central projection model, you'll note that the image is non-inverted
正如我们在上一次讲座中谈到的那样。我们可以写一个等式
as it was in the case that we talked about in the last lecture. We can write an equation
对于齐次坐标中的点P，我们乘以世界坐标X，Y，Z
for the point P in homogeneous coordinates, we multiply the world coordinates, X, Y, Z
通过3×4矩阵，以获得投影点的齐次坐标
by a 3 x 4 matrix in order to get the homogeneous coordinates of the projected point on the
图像平面。让我们稍微看一下这个等式
image plane. Let's look at this equation in a little bit
更多详情。用x，ỹ，z语言编写表达式非常简单
more detail. It's quite straightforward to write an expression for x̃, ỹ, z̃ in terms
焦距和世界坐标，X，Y，Z。我们可以改变同质
of the focal length and the world coordinate, X, Y, Z. We can transform the homogeneous
使用我们在最后讨论的规则坐标到笛卡尔坐标
coordinates to Cartesian coordinates using the rule that we talked about in the last
部分和一点点的重新排列，我们可以将方程带入这种形式和
section and with a little bit of rearrangement, we can bring the equation into this form and
这与我们在上一次演讲中通过观察相似的内容完全相同
this is exactly the same form as we derived in the last lecture by looking at similar
三角形。什么是非常方便和有用的
triangles. What's really convenient and useful about
图像形成过程的这种均匀表示是完全的
this homogeneous representation of the image formation process is that it is completely
线性的。我们没有这个明确的划分Z，相机和相机之间的距离
linear. We don't have this explicit division by Z, the distance between the camera and
物体。它隐含在我们以均匀形式编写方程的方式中。
the object. It's implicit in the way we write the equations in homogeneous form.
让我们再看一下这个等式，我们可以将这个矩阵分解为两个。矩阵上
Let's look at this equation again and we can factor this matrix into two. The matrix on
右边的元素是0或1或f，即镜头的焦距。所以这
the right has elements that are either 0 or 1 or f, the focal length of the lens. So this
矩阵执行缩放和缩放。这是我们镜头焦距的函数。
matrix performs the scaling and zooming. It’s a function of the focal length of our lens.
左边的矩阵有一个有趣的形状，它只有3x4和这个矩阵
The matrix on the left has got an interesting shape, it’s only a 3 x 4 and this matrix
执行维数减少，将点从三个维度缩减为两个。
performs the dimensionality reduction, crunches points from three dimensions down into two.
到目前为止，我们认为图像平面是连续的。实际上，图像平面
And so far, we consider the image plane to be continuous. In reality, the image plane
被量化。它由大量的光感应元件组成
is quantized. It consists of a massive array of light sensing elements which corresponds
到输出图像中的像素。这个网格中每个像素的尺寸，我要去
to the pixels in the output image. The dimension of each pixel in this grid, I’m going to
用希腊字母rho表示。所以像素很宽，而且它们很高。像素
denote by the Greek letter rho. So the pixels are rho u wide and they’re rho v high. Pixels
真的很小，所以像素的宽度和高度通常在大约的数量级
are really really small so the width and height of a pixel is often at the order of around
10微米，可能更大，可能更小一点。
10 microns, maybe a bit bigger, maybe a bit smaller.
我们现在需要做的是转换我们先前计算过的坐标P
What we need to do now is to convert the coordinate P which we computed previously and that was
以米为单位，相对于图像平面的原点。
in units of meters with respect to the origin of the image plane.
我们需要将它转换为像素单位，我们的像素坐标系有所不同
We need to convert it to units of pixels and our pixel coordinate system has got a different
我们在早期讲座中谈到的起源。像素坐标是从左上角开始测量的
origin as we talked about in earlier lectures. Pixel coordinates are measured from the top-left
图像的一角，所以我们需要做一个缩放，我们需要做一个移动，那就是
corner of the image so we need to do a scaling and we need to do a shifting and that’s
一个简单的线性操作。因此，如果我们有点的笛卡尔x和y坐标
a simple linear operation. So if we have the Cartesian x and y coordinates of the point
在图像平面上的P，我们可以将其转换为我们的等效像素坐标
P on the image plane, we can convert that to the equivalent pixel coordinate which we
用坐标u和v表示，我们可以再次以同质的形式表示。
denote by the coordinates u and v and we can represent that again in homogeneous form.
这里我们乘以矩阵，矩阵的元素是像素的维度
Here we multiplied by a matrix, the elements of the matrix are the dimensions of the pixel
Pu和Pv以及所谓的主要点的坐标。主要观点是
Pu and Pv and the coordinates of what’s called the principal point. The principal point is
相机原点z轴的像素坐标
the pixel coordinate where the z axis of the camera origin frame
刺穿图像平面。可以转换均匀像素坐标
pierces the image plane. The homogeneous pixel coordinates can be converted
通过我们的转换规则得到更熟悉的笛卡尔像素坐标u和v
to the more familiar Cartesian pixel coordinates u and v by the transformation rule that we
早先报道过。基本上，我们采取第一和第二
covered earlier. Essentially, we take the first and second
均匀向量的元素并将其除以齐次的第三个元素
element of the homogeneous vector and divide it by the third element of the homogeneous
向量。现在，我们可以将所有这些部分组合在一起
vector. Now, we can put all these pieces together
我们可以用三个矩阵来编写完整的相机模型。的产物
and we can write the complete camera model in terms of three matrices. The product of
前两个矩阵通常用符号K表示，我们将它们称为
the first two matrices is typically denoted by the symbol K and we refer to these as the
内在参数。这两个矩阵中的所有数字都是摄像机本身的功能。
intrinsic parameters. All the numbers in these two matrices are functions of the camera itself.
相机在哪里指向并不重要，它们只是一个功能
It doesn't matter where the camera is where it’s pointing, they’re only a function
相机这些数字包括图像平面上像素的高度和宽度，
of the camera. These numbers include the height and width of the pixels on the image plane,
主点的坐标和镜头的焦距。
the coordinates of the principal point and the focal length of the lens.
第三个矩阵描述了外部参数，这些参数描述了相机的位置
The third matrix describes the extrinsic parameters and these describe where the camera is but
他们没有说相机的类型。
they don’t say anything about the type of camera.
该矩阵中的元素是相机相对姿态的函数
The elements in this matrix are a function of the relative pose of the camera with respect
到世界起源框架。实际上，它与xiC相反。
to the world origin frame. In fact, it is the inverse of xi C.
所有这些矩阵的乘积一起被称为相机矩阵
The product of all of these matrices together is referred to as the camera matrix and it’s
经常给出符号C.所以这个单个矩阵，这个单个3x4矩阵
often given the symbol C. So this single matrix, this single 3 x 4 matrix
我们需要描述从世界坐标X，Y和Z到的映射
is all we need to describe the mapping from a world coordinate, X, Y and Z through to
图像平面上像素坐标的均匀表示。那是同质的
a homogeneous representation of the pixel coordinate on the image plane. That homogeneous
图像平面坐标可以转换为熟悉的笛卡尔图像平面坐标
image plane coordinate can be converted to the familiar Cartesian image plane coordinate
在这里使用此转换规则。所以这是一种非常简单和简洁的表现方式
using this transformation rule here. So this is a very simple and concise way of performing
透视投影。现在让我们考虑一下我介绍时会发生什么
perspective projection. Let’s consider now what happens when I introduce
非零比例因子λ。齐次坐标元素ũ，ṽ和w将
a non-zero scale factor λ. The homogeneous coordinate elements ũ, ṽ and w̃ will
全部按λ缩放。当我将它们转换为笛卡尔形式时，λ项将被考虑
all be scaled by λ. When I convert them to Cartesian form, the λ term will be factored
out，它在分子和分母中，所以结果将保持不变。这是一个特别的
out, it's in the numerator and the denominator so the result will be unchanged. This is a particular
以同质形式写关系的好处。它给了我们所谓的缩放方差。
advantage of writing the relationship in homogeneous form. It gives us what’s called scaling variance.
因为我们可以将矩阵乘以任意值
Because we can multiply the matrix by an arbitrary
比例因子，这意味着我们可以用稍微简化的形式写出相机矩阵
scale factor, it means we can write the camera matrix in a slightly simplified form, which
我们称之为标准化相机矩阵。我们选择一个特定的元素来做到这一点
we refer to as a normalized camera matrix. We do that by choosing one particular element
该矩阵的值为1，通常我们选择右下角的元素并将其设置为1。
of that matrix to have a value of 1 and typically we choose the bottom right element and set it to 1.
此标准化相机矩阵仍包含
This normalized camera matrix still contains
所有信息都完整地描述了图像形成过程。它包含
all of the information to completely describe the image formation process. It contains the
镜头的焦距，它包含像素的尺寸，它包含
focal length of the lens, it contains the dimensions of the pixels, it contains the
主点的坐标，它包含摄像机的位置和方向
coordinate of the principal point and it contains the position and orientation of the camera
在三维空间。最后，我们可以转换齐次像素坐标
in three dimensional space. And finally, we can convert the homogeneous pixel coordinates
我们用u和v表示更熟悉的笛卡尔像素坐标。
to the more familiar Cartesian pixel coordinates which we denote by u and v.